

Summary

Skills

Tuan Linh

Business Analyst

Email: tuanlinh1404@gmail.com

Phone: +84 909 420 198 **Skype:** live:tuanlinh1404

I'm an experienced business analyst in the computer software industry with domain knowledge in:

- Financial Institutions
- Banking
- Customer Relationship Management
- Medical support industries.

I'm familiar with all stages of the software development life cycle, including Agile process and testing process.

Year of experience in Business Analyst role:

- Verbal and written communication in English (IELTS 6.0)
- Familiar with both Waterfall and Agile process
- Experience in using Documenting/Diagramming tools
- Advanced use of JIRA, Microsoft Excel, Word

Experience with all stages of the software development life cycle in the Agile process & testing process.

Have experienced in several domains such as Banking, Bills and Finance, Medicine, Customer Relationship Management, Real-estate.

Advance in reporting tools: Jira, GitHub.

Automation & Manual Tester for over 2 years of experience:

- Robot Framework in Python
- Selenium in Java/C#

Having knowledge in testing Web Application, Hybrid Mobile Application, and Window Application.

Entry-level data analytics professional.

Experience

Aperia Solutions / Business Analyst

Jul 2021 - Jul 2022, Vietnam

Project domain: Banking and financial web application Responsibilities:

- Gather, analyze, clarify and refine requirements from clients
- Work together with develop team to bring out solutions
- Host Agile ceremonies, sprint planning and retrospective
- Demonstrate app features to product manager and clients
- Create functional specification document:
 - Use cases, flows, states diagrams
 - Co-op with Designer for application UI/UX
- Support function/feature testing
- Report to Product Manager about Sprint's accomplish ability, status of features, stories, bug fixes and test cases.

Technology: React, .NET

Member size: 7

FPT University / Capstone Project Leader

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020, Vietnam

Project domain: B2B Group Buying System

Responsibilities:

- Gather, analyze and clarify requirements
- Design system model, architecture, database and core flows
- Review and track team members' process
- Technical documentation:
 - Create Software Requirement Specification
 - Design and create Use cases diagram
 - Draw Entity Relationship diagram, class diagram
 - Draw Sequence diagram, Flow diagram
- Analyze, create and execute test cases

Technology: React, Javascript, .Net, Microsoft SQL Server, Firebase

Member size: 4

TMA Solutions / Automation Tester

Sep 2019 - Jul 2020, Vietnam

Project domain: Fitness appointment hybrid application Responsibilities:

- Design and develop automation scripts
- Execute automation test suites
- Extract test reports and analyze
- Investigate issues, bugs and give feedbacks

Technology: Robot Framework, Katalon Groovy and Selenium C#

Tools: Katalon Studio, Visual Studio Code, Postman

Member size: 10

TMA Solutions / Technical Writer

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018, Vietnam

Project domain: Medical support web application

Responsibilities:

- Clear understanding and knowledge of product
- Technical documentation
- Develop product manuals, guides, help sections

Member size: 5

TMA Solutions / Manual Tester

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018, Vietnam

Project domain: Bills and financial management mobile application

Responsibilities:

- Analyzing requirements from client
- Create test cases and review them
- Execute test cases and tracking defects

Tools: Apache JMeter

Member size: 15

Education

Google Data Analytics Certificate

March 2023 - April 2023, Online

As a fast-learner, I've recently completed the six-month Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate.

FPT University / Bachelor of Software Engineering

Jan 2017 - Dec 2020, Ho Chi Minh City